FABRIZIO M. POMATA

FULL STACK WEB DEVELOPER • ASUNCIÓN, PARAGUAY

• DETAILS •

Asunción Paraguay garak92@protonmail.com

LINKS

Github Repo

Personal Website

YouTube Channel

SKILLS

React

JavaScript

Node.js

Python

SQL

Git

MongoDB

Redux

Linux

Docker

GraphQL

Redis

LANGUAGES

English

Spanish

Italian

PROFILE

Software developer with 4+ YOE ranging from full-stack web development to data engineering. Led a team that developed applications and reports for the company, helped surpass company goals for 2 years by 10% and 3% respectively, achieved a 30% reduction in bug rates, and 20% increased response time in React/Redux components, and authored and maintained an internal library that increased the development speed of one of the sub-teams by 50%.

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

Head of BI & Software Development at Tecnoedil S.A., Asunción

January 2020 — October 2022

- Created and managed the Department of BI and Software Development at the company, achieving 100% of the objectives each year
- Built, improved and helped deploy more than 20 containerized Node.js micro-services
- Brought many full-stack React/Node apps from 0 to 1
- Refactored multiple parts of the code base according to standards and best practices, increasing developer productivity up to 15%
- Maintained, unit-tested, and debugged all of the enterprise's web applications, resulting in a 30% bug rate decrease over time
- Improved the performance of many React/Redux components, increasing the response times up to 20%
- Built an internal Python tool that helped the BI team write and debug ETL processes 50% faster
- Conducted the initiative to create a knowledge base for the team, reducing on-boarding time by 40%, and speeding up debugging
- Created and maintained the company's enterprise data warehouse and Power BI Reports, which was instrumental in achieving 2 years of surpassed company goals (by 10% the first year, and 3% the second year)

Data Engineer at Netsystem S.A., Asunción

September 2017 — December 2019

- Designed and developed dimensional data warehouses and data pipelines for customers ranging from pharmaceutical industries to law firms, successfully completing more than 15 projects
- Designed and delivered Power BI/DAX courses and open talks for many renowned local companies, increasing the client portfolio up to 13%, which led to approximately 10% more yearly profit margin in new contracts
- Optimized a Power BI report for a big customer, achieving a 50% performance increase

EDUCATION

Licenciatura in Philosophy, Universidad Católica Nuestra Senora de la Asunción, Asunción

January 2010 — September 2015

Graduated with a thesis on Bertrand Russell's scientific realism

★ SOFT SKILLS

• 2 years of experience leading a team of developers & coordinating efforts with other departments

- Successfully managed many projects both in a team and independently for more than 4 years
- +4 YOE communicating ideas and defending proposals to colleagues and customers from all backgrounds using presentations and other means
- Excellent understanding of administrative, financial, and accounting concepts thanks to extensive data experience